

M.Sc. Software Engineer · Software Craftsperson - Product Minded Full-Stack Polyglot Web Developer - Certified CKAD

🛘 request with a message | 🎢 Amsterdam / The Netherlands - HSM Visa | 🔀 hi@alpcoker.com | 🚱 alpcoker.com | 🖸 alpcoker | 🛅 alpcoker

Bio - Background

I'm a software craftsperson who loves to be at the center of creating software that provides value for humanity, makes companies more profitable, or increases their efficiency. I always think about creating an impact on existing circumstances. I identify myself as a problem solver rather than a specific tech fanatic. I apply the most optimum solution when and where necessary.

I have fourteen years of experience and worked for seven companies from start-ups to big enterprise companies. I have worked in the following industries; people management solution, cryptocurrency, travel, defense, government, and geographic information systems. I have worked in onsite, remote, and cross-continent company environments. I have both experience in synchronous and asynchronous development environments.

As hobby project/product, I am developing widely used open-source project 🗹. I also have some achievements in some competitions.

Career Objectives

I love to apply my skills to help our(my) projects reach their goals. I will be satisfied if my output is used by other people and it is completing our goals one by one. I always try to put my best effort to reach desired quality for any kind of work in our remaining time.

I always try/want to be (stay as) an innovative and target-driven engineer. I seek better solutions, and best practices not just in my career, but also apply them to my life. I look for new challenges, goals, and responsibilities that can keep me active and fresh in my life. While I am working with my colleagues, I always try to move/develop/focus together. Because no significant success can be attributed to a single person.

Experience

Tesla 🗹 - People Management Solution - Electric Cars, Solar & Clean Energy

Amsterdam, Netherlands

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL-STACK)

Jan. 2023 - ongoing

- I am working on an in-house people management solution that automates the whole company's internal processes. I have end to end responsibilities in one of the internal application that involves many internal & external stakeholders. *Confidential*
- Used technologies: .NET 8, React, Angular, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Elastic Stack, Redis, Jenkins, GitHub Enterprise, Splunk, Atlassian Products

BtcTurk - Cryptocurrency Exchange & Platform - Highest Cryptocurrency Volume in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (BACK-END)

Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- I worked on the cash flow team. I was responsible for fiat deposits and withdrawals on a cryptocurrency exchange which has a very high market value. The platform was using a microservices architecture. I was developing and monitoring the system's health.
- Used technologies: .NET 6, RabbitMQ, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure, Elastic Stack, Redis, Atlassian Products

Otelz - Online Travel Agency - Most Popular in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL-STACK)

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2022

- I independently developed <u>Expedia</u> integration to enable company to expand abroad. Company list hotels not just in Turkey but in world. This included data sync between <u>different</u> company models, searching, listing hotel availability, processing payments, handling reservations.
- I developed a new channel manager (a system for hotels to manage their availability in real-time) integration that is widely used by big resorts. For our existing channel manager integrations with a count of 25, I maintained and monitored them.
- · Used technologies: .NET 5, React, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure DevOps, Elastic Stack, AWS, Redis, Atlassian Products

T2 🗹 - Defence Industry Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL-STACK)

Aug. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- I redesigned the architecture of their mission critical desktop systems for their intranet web environment.
- · Used technologies: React, Java 11, Spring, Kotlin, TimescaleDB with PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack, GitLab Enterprise

Havelsan 🗹 - Defence Industry - Reference: Hülya Vural - Software Engineering Manager 🗷

Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ARCHITECT)

May 2017 - Aug. 2020

- Responsible for designing architecture, defining standards, improving performance, fixing security flaws, implementing new features.
- Used technologies: ASP.NET Core 3.1, ASP.NET MVC, Angular, Oracle Database, Elastic Stack, Redis, Team Foundation Server

BilgeAdam 🗗 - Outsourcing for Government Offices - Reference: Seçkin Bedük - Software Development Director 🗗

Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR SOFTWARE CONSULTANT (FULL-STACK)

Aug. 2014 - May 2017

- I replaced a high traffic government public service with a new modern architecture to solve previous maintenance difficulties.
- Used technologies: Windows Presentation Foundation, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server, SQL Server Integration Services, Team Foundation Server

Başarsoft ☑ - Geographic Information System Company - Reference: Emrah Yılmaz - R&D Manager ☑

Ankara, Turkey

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (MOBILE & SERVICES)

Feb. 2010 - Jan. 2014

• I developed Windows CE, Windows Mobile, tablet applications which are connected and navigation systems customized by customer needs.

Used technologies: .NET Compact Framework, ASP.NET Web Services, SQL Server, Oracle, TCP/IP, ASP.NET, Team Foundation Server.

OSS - Open Source Software

photo-cli 🗹

Well-documented, widely used open-source tool for a photo archiving & management tool. I started development for my personal need not to use any third-party cloud provider to store all my photo archive. I open-source this tool by targeting a high quality code & documented it well.

A photo organizer for your file system without sticking to any application or vendor. Extract when and where (reverse geocoding) your photos are taken, copy into a new organized folder with various folder & file naming strategies, export into CSV files.

Skills (w/years of experience)

Languages C# (13), JavaScript(9), Typescript(5), Python(2), Rust(1), Golang(1), Kotlin(1), Java(1), R(1)

.NET(13), ASP.NET(10), React(4), Angular(2), Vue.js(1), HTTP-REST API(9), OAuth-OIDC(2), WPF(4), Windows Forms(3), Spring **Technologies**

Boot(1), Hadoop(1), Spark(1), HTML(9), CSS(5)

Microservices(6), Message Broker(5), Hexagonal(2), Miniservices(2), CQS & CQRS(2), Monolithic(9), Layered & n-tier(8), MVC(3), **Architecture**

Service-Oriented Architecture(4), Modular(4), Client-Server(2), Outbox(1), TDD(1), Strangler(1), API Composition(1)

SDLC Rapid application development(5), Kanban(3), Scrum(2), Extreme Programming(2), Spiral Model(1)

Database MS-SQL Server(10), PostgreSQL(7), Elastic Search(6), Redis(6), Oracle(4), MongoDB(3), MySQL(3), Prometheus(2), HBase(1) **Platforms** Kubernetes(4), Kibana(6), RabbitMQ(3), Grafana(3), Kafka(2), Splunk(2), Fluentd(1), Camunda Workflow(1), Jaeger(1)

Azure DevOps-TFS(8), Docker(7), Linux(7), Git(5), GitHub(4), AWS(2), Azure(1), Heroku(1), GitLab(2), Atlassian(2), NGINX(2), NPM(1), **DevOps**

Jenkins(2)

Rider(8), WebStorm(5), PyCharm(3), DataGrip(5), VS Code(5), Linux(10), Windows(20), macOS(3), Visual Studio(10) Tools

Achievements

Third place with our team, Havelsan Hackathon 2020

Ankara, Turkey Istanbul, Turkey

2010 Finalist with our team, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2010

Competition Winner Istanbul, Turkey

May. 2009 MICROSOFT & TURKCELL

• I have participated and won first place in a Mobile Application Development Competition which was hosted by Microsoft and Turkcell. My application is a social network for Windows Mobile users who can create places and fill out profiles to be searched by others. They can also share and tweet their locations within the application. This application was very similar to Foursquare/Swarm before they exists.

Education

2010-2013 Master of Science in Computer Engineering, Çankaya University (GPA 3,6 over 4) 2006-2010 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, Çankaya University (GPA 3,2 over 4)

Ankara, Turkey Ankara, Turkey

Volunteer Work

Mentor in ADPList 🗗 Platform that connects aspiring people with experienced mentors for personalized guidance and support in their careers.

Mentor in SisterLabs Tech Academy Project & Supported by Community Volunteers Foundation, is a project that aims to contribute to the empowerment of young women between the ages of 20-28 who are 3rd & 4th-year university students or university graduates to participate in the workforce in the software industry.

Certifications

2016

CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (2), Linux Foundation 2023

Linux Foundation MongoDB University

2018 M001: Basics 4, M101P: Developers 4, M201: Performance 4, MongoDB University The Data Scientist's Toolbox, 🕘, R Programming 🕘, Getting and Cleaning Data 🕘,

Exploratory Data Analysis 🕘, Reproducible Research 🕘, Graph Analytics for Big Data 🕘, Hadoop Platform and Application Framework 🕘, Introduction to Big Data Analytics 🕘,

Introduction to Big Data 4, Machine Learning With Big Data 4, Machine Learning: Regression 4,

Machine Learning: Classification 4, Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach 4, Data Structures and Algorithms 🕘, Algorithmic Toolbox 🕘 , Johns Hopkins University, University of California, University of Washington

Computational Thinking and Data Science 🕘 , Computer Science and Programming Using Python 🕘 ,

2015 Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Coursera

edX